Direct your attention to the book of
Joshua chapter 1
and verse 8.
the verse 8.
This book of the law shall not depart
from your mouth,
but you shall meditate in it day and
night, that you may observe to do
according to all that is written in it.
For then you will make your way
prosperous.
Somebody say, I'll be prosperous.
>> I'll be prosperous.
>> Can you shout, I'll be prosperous.
And then you will have
good
success.
Good. Not just success, but good
success. Uh, put your finger there and
jump over to the book of 1 Corinthians
chapter 9 verse 24- 27.
1 Corinthians chapter 9
24-27
the Bible says do you not know that
those who run in a race all run
but one
receives the prize.
run in such a way
that you may obtain it.
And everyone who competes for the prize
is temporate in all things.
Now they do it to obtain a perishable
crown, but we
for an imperishable
crown.
Therefore, I run thus not with
uncertainty.
Thus I fight not as one who beats the
air,
but I discipline my body and bring it
into subjection, lest when I have
preached to others, I myself
should become disqualified. Father,
bless the reading of your word to our
hearts this morning. Receive all the
praise and the glory
in Jesus name I pray. Somebody say amen.
And amen. You may be seated in the
presence of the Lord.
I want to speak this morning on the
subject I've entitled the discipline
of success.
The discipline
My brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen, I submit to you this morning
that success is not an accident.
Success is not flukes.
Success is not a happen stance.
Success does not happen because you went
to sleep and then you know hocus pocus
you wake up and you are successful.
Please listen to me this morning.
Success is a product of discipline.
Help me preach and turn to your
neighbor. Tell them success
is a product
of discipline.
For you see, while many admire
successful people, few are willing to
embrace the habits,
sacrifices,
and consistencies
required to achieve success. I repeat,
few are willing to embrace the habits
of successful people, the sacrifices
they make and consistencies that it
needs to be successful.
God has a plan for his children
and the plan that God has for you is to
prosper you and fulfill
your purpose here on earth. But that
journey requires discipline.
The book of Joshua chapter 1 and verse 8
says, "This book of the law shall not
depart from your mouth,
but you shall meditate in it day
and night.
Then you will make your way prosperous
and then you will have good success.
My brothers and sisters this morning
even as introduced my message notice
that God connects success
with discipline. God connects success
with
discipline.
For you see, for you to be successful,
there are a number of areas where you
need to be disciplined.
Success requires first and foremost
self
discipline. 1 Corinthians chapter 9 and
verse 25 says, "Everyone who competes
for the prize is temporate
in all things."
An athlete does not become a champion by
desire alone.
An athlete does not say well I desire to
be a winner.
A boxer does not say I desire to be a
heavyweight uh boxing champion.
It takes discipline
that causes them to go
exercise practice for them to win.
Yes. Success demands control over your
emotions.
Success demands control over your
appetites.
Success demands control over your time.
Success demands
control over your words.
Self discipline is so crucial for you to
be successful.
You will not be a successful person if
you're not going to be disciplined. Now,
I know a lot of churches will not teach
you this, but let me teach you the
truth. Somebody say, "Teach us the
truth." You can be anointed until the
oil is finished in the refinery. If you
are not disciplined, you will not be
successful. For the Bible teaches us
that uh if you're going to be successful
and that he who competes must be
temporary in all things. In all of
things it means that you've got to be
disciplined. And so you've got to be
disciplined in your emotions. You've got
to be disciplined in your appetites.
You've got to be disciplined in your
time. And you've got to be disciplined
uh in your words.
A lack of discipline destroys potential.
I repeat, a lack of discipline destroys
potential.
So self discipline
is an imperative
if you're going to be successful.
I am a strong believer that people are
separated, those who make it in life and
those who don't, simply because of what
I call self-discipline.
If you have had the opportunity of
interacting with successful people, one
of the qualities that stands out is that
they are actually very disciplined
people. They are disciplined with their
time. You cannot waste their time. They
are disciplined with how they think.
They are disciplined with their
emotions. They are disciplined with how
they spend their money. Yes. If you're
going to BE SUCCESSFUL, YOU'VE GOT to
have this imperative of being uh self
disciplined.
Could it be you're where you are today
because you're not self-disciplined?
Could it be that you're where you are
because simply discipline has eluded you
and you have not embraced it?
As I look at Christians as a pastor for
many many years, uh I see so many people
who have been eluded by success simply
because they have no discipline. And
discipline actually shows up in a lot of
areas. In fact, let me hasten to add
here. If you're not disciplined, you
will not be disciplined at all in all
areas. It will show up in your
activities. It will show up in your
work. It will show up in your
relationship. It will show up wherever
you go. Are you disciplined? For if
you're going to be successful, you can
pray, you can jump, you can sit down,
you can kneel. If you're not
disciplined, you will not
be successful.
You will not be successful.
But success requires also consistency.
Many people start
well but fail because they lack
consistency. Galatians chapter 6 and
verse 9. Let us not grow weary while
doing good. For in due season we shall
reap if we do not lose heart. I repeat,
let us not grow weary while doing good.
For in due season we shall reap if we do
not lose heart.
Great achievements
are the results of small faithful
actions repeated daily. Great
achievements
are the results of small
faithful actions repeated
daily.
Small faithful actions repeated
A lot of people fail to reach their
goals because they set up goals they're
not able to keep.
You cannot wake up this morning and tell
me that you're going to walk for 15
kilometers every day and you don't even
walk for 300 m a day. But if you set up
small
faithful actions that are
able
that you are able rather to keep, you
will make it. Yes.
Successful people show up when they
don't feel like it because they are
consistent. Successful people pray when
they are tired because they are
consistent. Success successful people
work when others procrastinate because
they are consistent and successful
people continue when others quit because
they're consistent.
Are you consistent?
Because successful people
are
consistent
people.
Yes,
successful people require
sacrifice.
Every success story
has a sacrifice
behind it.
Every success story has a sacrifice
behind it. Luke chapter 9 and verse 23
says, "If anyone desires to come after
me, let him deny himself
and take up his cross
daily."
See, you cannot have great a great
future rather while refusing to give up
distractions,
laziness
and comfort.
Sometimes success
costs
will cost you your sleep.
It will cost you entertainment.
Success will cost you immediate
gratification
and success will cost you convenience.
Those people who have done exams and I
know there are many here.
You remember the midnight oil you used
to burn.
You sacrifice
a lot
for your master's degree.
You sacrificed time.
You delayed gratification
so that you can be in the books
and make sure that you graduate.
When I was in college, it was a
competition.
We used to compete who's going to be
number one.
And to be able to come number one,
people would study even on Saturdays and
Sundays
because the competition was tight,
delaying gratification.
I think I talked to some people long
time ago and I told them it's a danger
to eat your dinner at breakfast.
Meaning that those people who don't
delay gratification
end up messing up
on their journey of success.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen, you have to sacrifice if
you're going to be successful.
Some of you will have to sacrifice the
goodies of life. You have to sacrifice
by uh saving some money. You have to
sacrifice by not uh having everything
everybody's having around so that you
can get what you really want. Because to
be successful, you have to sacrifice.
You cannot be a success if you're not
sacrificing something. There will be
something that you will sacrifice.
It may be sleep. It may it may be
entertainment. It may be uh
gratification. It may be convenience.
whatever it is,
but you'll have to sacrifice to get it.
What are you
unwilling to sacrifice
for your growth
in the discipline
of success?
Success requires time management.
Ephesians 5:15-16,
the Bible talks about redeeming the time
because the days are evil.
Time is life's most valuable resource.
I repeat, time
is life's most
valuable
resource.
It's better for somebody to steal your
money and not your time.
It's better for somebody to steal even
your car and not your time.
For once they steal your time, they've
stolen your life.
Once they've taken your time, wasted
your time, uh they have wasted your
life.
Time is precious.
People dying in hospital just crave and
pray that they will just be added uh
another day,
but they can't have it.
Some pray for hours,
but they can't have it. Some pray that
it can be just delayed a bit so that the
family members can come and they can
beat each other. Bye-bye. But they can't
have it. Time is precious. Time ticks uh
tick tock tick tock. It ticks tick tock
tick tock. I was reading yesterday about
uh
passenger who's 90 some something some
years 90 something years old and he was
saying uh time is like a blink of the
eye.
Time is like a blink of the eye.
You were young yesterday. You're not
young today.
Listen to me.
And that time is ticking and time is
going. You have no business wasting any
more time. The time you have wasted is
enough.
And before long you will be out of the
stage.
And it will be sad for you to be out of
the stage because you did not manage
your time well. Are you listening to me
this morning?
Time is ticking.
I saw yesterday a documentary of a lion.
A lion that used to be very voros,
strong,
muscular
when it was young,
hunting, and it could get whatever it
wanted to eat.
But as time passed on, that same strong
vibos lion got weaker and weaker. With
time passing,
the lion could not hunt like it used to
hunt anymore.
The lion could not catch prey like it
would catch anymore.
It became frail and thin and could not
eat,
could not even walk with strength.
Eventually, the lion just went by the
side of the road, laid down, and died.
What happened? time
had elapsed for it to be strong and to
do the things that it used to do uh and
to get the pray that it used to get. I
am talking to you today, you will
remember me.
You will remember this sermon that the
time that you're wasting one time you
will regret. This is the time for you to
do what you need to do. It is not time
to pro procrastinate. It is not time to
postpone. It is time for you to do what
you need to do. If you need to go back
to school, go back to school. If you
need to build, start building. Whatever
you need to do, START NOW. STOP WASTING
your time. People who are successful
manage their time. Well,
somebody who's 95 something years is
telling you that he can't remember how
time went because just time flew. I was
reading that yesterday.
Time just flew and now he's 95 and he
can't even believe.
If I was to pick people here today in
this service and ask you, can you
actually calculate how time has gone?
You will be shocked. You yourself are
shocked that you are this old.
Because when you are 12, you used to
hear somebody's 20 and you used to say
they old.
My goodness. How are they 30?
How can she be 30?
I'm only 15.
Now you yourself
are at 30.
I was at the pastors and bishops retreat
the other day. I mean, I came in last
night. I was there for 4 days. All
right.
And I'm seeing some of the pastors who
came here as young people now they have
white hair. And I told them my goodness
you have developed white hair now.
Now I know ministry is tough but it's
ministry besides besides ministry it's
JUST THE ISSUE OF time is moving so
fast. Time is ticking. Time is going.
PEOPLE WHO ARE SUCCESSFUL MUST maximize
on managing time.
Things will pass you.
THE BIBLE SAYS HE GIVES TIME AND chance
to everybody. GOD IS NOT UNFAITHFUL. GOD
IS JUST. HE GIVES time and chance to
everybody. There's nobody who is not
going to make it who will blame God.
Even the Jangakar rooms who never went
to school use their time to become
billionaires.
Time and chance.
People who are successful manage
time.
You will remember me.
You will remember me. I am telling you,
you will remember me.
time.
My mother used to tell me the beauty of
ladies is nothing. I used to say, "Mom,
what are you talking about?
What are you saying, mommy? The beauty
of a lady is nothing." He says, "It is
nothing because it comes and evaporates
so quickly." My mother used to tell me
that as a boy.
IT COMES AND EVAPORATES SO QUICKLY.
She was never taught that in school
is what she had observed.
Comes quickly and before you know it, it
is gone.
People who are successful
manage
their time well.
I mean even me
there are things which if I didn't do
when I did them I would never do them.
I can not do them now
because time and chance
he gives
to them all.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen,
if you're going to be successful
in this life,
you have also
to grow.
Proverbs chapter 1 and verse 5 says, "A
wise man will hear and increase
learning."
Successful people never stop learning. I
repeat, successful people never stop
learning.
The day you stop learning is the day you
start dying.
They stay I repeat again the day you
stop learning is the day you start
dying.
You may not die physically but you will
die in your intellect
and in your intelligence here.
So successful people read books,
seek mentors,
welcome correction,
learn from failures.
I was telling the pastors and bishops in
the retreat,
learning has been made so easy today.
In our day and age, I used to go to
America every year to conferences and
seminars. Every year
I used to go,
you have to pay your air ticket. You
have to pay your hotel. You have to pay
your upkeep in America. All those
things.
Now you don't have to get an air ticket
and go and pay up hotels. It's all
available to you on your phone.
Knowledge is available on your phone.
Conferences are available on your phone.
Seminars are available on your phone.
teachers, mentors are available on your
phone. You don't have to jump from here
to go to the US or England or Australia,
wherever it is. Take hours in the plane,
go apply visas and apply for hours, wake
up at 5:00 to go and queue at the
American embassy. All of it is on the
phone. You have no excuse not to grow
mentally.
You have no excuse to be ignorant.
And by the way, for your information, we
are living in the super information age.
We are in the information age.
We have even actually passed
technological age. We are in in the
information age now
where you have no excuse to be ignorant.
Look at your neighbor, tell them you
have no excuse to be ignorant.
Oh, come on. Ignorance just rubs me the
wrong way myself.
I am allergic to ignorant people. I'm
really allergic. I mean, if you're
working for me and you're ignorant, you
will see the wrong side of me.
Because the first thing I'm going to ask
you, what are you thinking to be able to
do that? Why are you doing that?
Because you should be able to know
better. In the information age,
you have no reason to be ignorant.
Successful people are knowledgeable
people. Are you listening to me? House
of Grace. You read books. You look for
mentors. You hear my messages. Go to
Facebook. Go to House of Grace page.
Listen to me over and over and over
just in case there's a point that passed
you. Listen to me.
I'm I'm I'm a think I don't brag a lot,
but if only you listen to me, you're
going to be good.
>> Is that true?
>> If just listen to me, just listen to me.
Just just go to to House of Grace page
and just listen to me. When you have
time, just create time. What was Bishop
talking about? What did he talk about?
Uh, you know the discipline of success.
Let me listen to him again.
And then that time you can criticize me.
Now you can't.
Are you listening? And go over and over
because what I come to preach to you is
thoroughly researched.
THOROUGHLY. ALL YOU NEED TO DO IS JUST
to feed. Just feed. Somebody has done
all the work for you. All you need to do
is just to feed.
I mean it's like a chef who has taken
time to go through the recipe. He has
gone cook for you and all you need to do
is just sit on the table and eat.
What more can somebody do?
So if I see some children are getting
thin and they're not getting, you know,
healthy, it's not the food.
It's not the food for sure because some
are doing very well in this church.
There are so so many people doing very
very well in their places of work. There
are people WHO ARE SUCCEEDING SO WELL IN
THIS CHURCH. THERE are people who are
having impact in this church. But there
are people who are doing nothing and
they have fed the same food.
Hello. Somebody say ouch.
You will not be in that category of
people who are not doing good.
>> Can I hear a loud amen?
>> How can you be in the same church
and you have millionaires and you've got
people who are begging for bas and I'm
feeding them the same food?
Somebody say I refuse.
>> I refuse.
>> Successful people
they are HUNGRY FOR INFORMATION. THEY UH
THEY HAVE AN APPETITE FOR JUST knowing
what needs to be known. Uh they are they
have never arrived in knowledge. They
keep on. When I graduated from college,
my professor said this IS NOT THE END OF
LEARNING.
They gave you the degree and told you
this is not
the end of learning.
Successful people
are growing
are growing. But successful people also
grow spiritually
because you've got to understand that
success is from God.
So you have to grow your spiritual life.
You have to grow your spiritual life.
And the way you grow your spiritual life
is by prayer.
You have to be a person who prays
because success comes from God. Grow
your spiritual life. Bible study,
fasting, worship, and fellowship.
Matthew chapter 6 and verse 33 says,
"Seek first the kingdom of God and his
righteousness, and all these things
shall be added to you." Matthew chapter
6 and verse 33. I repeat, seek first the
kingdom of God and his righteousness,
and all these things shall be added unto
you. Yes, successful people grow their
spiritual lives. They have a discipline
in growing their spiritual lives. They
have a discipline when it comes to their
prayer life. They have a discipline when
it comes to Bible study. They have a
discipline when it comes to fasting.
They have a discipline. They have
adopted when it comes to their worship
to God. And they have a discipline when
it comes uh to fellowship.
But then also successful people
have a discipline of perseverance.
James 1 and verse 12 says, "Blessed is
the man who endures temptation, for when
he has been approved, he will receive
the crown of life."
Every successful person encounters
delays,
criticisms,
failure,
opposition.
The difference is that disciplined
people refuse to quit.
Disciplined people refuse
to quit.
You will encounter delay.
You will encounter criticism.
You will encounter failure.
You will encounter opposition.
But if you're going to be disciplined
and focused
on your journey to success, you will
refuse to quit.
Please remember,
failure is not falling down, but failure
is refusing to get up again. I repeat,
failure is not falling down. Failure is
refusing
to get up again.
Yeah. You have to be a person who
perseveres
to the very end.
The discipline of success
is doing what is necessary even when it
is difficult. I repeat the discipline of
success is doing what is necessary
even when
it is difficult. Success is not a
miracle.
It is the harvest of disciplined choices
made over time.
Maybe some Christians need to hear that
success is not a miracle. It is the
harvest of disciplined choices made
over
time.
If you're going to be successful,
I submit to you, you have to inculcate
the discipline
of success, which is self- discipline,
which is consistency,
which is sacrifice,
which is time management,
which is learning to grow.
growing your spiritual lives because
success is from God and persevering
to the end. These are the foundational
stones
for you
to succeed in life. I pray you succeed
in your life
>> in Jesus name.
>> I pray you'll be successful in Jesus
name. Can you shout a big amen? I pray
that you'll be on top in the name of
Jesus. and not under in the name of
Jesus.
>> Hallelujah. Stand up on your feet. Give
Jesus a round of applause because you're
going to be successful in the name of
Jesus.
Hallelujah.
[applause]
[music]
As you stand up, allow me to ask you,
what habit is limiting
your success?
What discipline do you need
to develop
to be successful?
What distractions
must you remove
to be successful?
Are you willing to pay the price
for the future God
has prepared
for you? Are you willing to pay the
price for the future that God
has prepared
for you? I repeat, are you willing to
pay the price for the future God has
prepared
for you? Let's pray. Father, in the name
of Jesus, I thank you. I bless you. I
worship you.
I've done my job. Oh God,
it's up to them now to know what they
will do with your word.
Have your way Lord and remember mercy.
Thank you King of glory for this time of
gathering together.
Pray Lord Jesus Christ that your people
will have the revelation that these are
foundational stones which they need to
be able to be successful and not just
pray about something that will never
happen without discipline because you've
told us Lord a person who wins in your
scripture
must be temperate must be disciplined
help us Lord in Jesus name I pray. Amen.
Please appreciate Jesus Christ one more
time. [applause]
Amen.